Xiaoxia Cheng

Montreal, QC, Canada (514) 586-8226 jenniferyao1996@hotmail.COM Jennifer-portfolio-cxxyao2.vercel.app

Apply for positions

Front-end developer, technical support engineer, QA engineer

Summary

Rich experience in developing, implementing and maintaining complex software projects. Now focus on frontend frameworks including Angular 6+, React, Next.js. Use Node.js and PHP in backend development as needed.

Solid knowledge of OOP, design patterns, databases(Oracle, Mysql, Sql server, MongoDB), RESTful api, GraphQL. Experience in automation tests using Karma, jasmine, jest and cypress.

Experience in Git-based Microsoft development environment Azure Devops and agile development.

A good team worker, self-driven, always professional and enthusiastic.

Skills

- 10 Years: c#/.net, Oracle, MS Sql Server
- 4 Years: Typescript, Javascript, CSS, SASS, HTML5, Bootstrap Css, Github
- 3 Years:React, Mysql, Postman, Bootstrap, Redux, Angular 6+, Ngrs, Mongo, Node.js
- 1 Year: NGXS, Cypress, jest, Karma, Firestore, Tailwind Css
- Experienced in Next.js ,PHP, AJAX, JQuery

Experience

Nov 2021 - July 2022

ADNM.NET, Montreal, Canada - Frontend developer

- Tech stack: Angular 12+, React, Next.js, Bootstrap CSS, SASS, NGXS, Cypress, Karma, Swagger, c#
- Help the team release the new version on time. Add state management (NGXS) to 20% components (Total: 150+)
- Troubleshot bugs or flaws mainly related to asynchronous processing and responsive UI
- Optimize performance cooperating with backend developers
- Contribute to system test and documentation
- Develop new user-specific features

Aug 2014 - Oct 2022

A learner and freelancer

- Take a career break to take care of my family. Take full-time french courses
- Take high quality online courses to systematically learn Javascript and related frontend frameworks
- Work as a volunteer to develop an online article repository using PHP, Mysql ,React and Storybook, AJAX, JQuery, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap.

Oct 2014- July 2018

Yonyou company, Shanghai - Technical Consultant

- Tech Stack: Java, Html, MS project, Geographic Map
- Participate in creating and executing ERP system implement plans
- Work closely with development team and end-users to ensure deliver right CRM product
- Train users and new employees in best practice to utilize ERP to its fullest capacity
- Help accounts well adapt to financial policy changes by configuring reports on BI platform
- Help salespersons increase lead, accelerate orders, manage accounts receivable and commission

Oct 2001 - Sep 2014

CITS company, Shanghai - Senior Software Engineer and Project manager

- Tech stack: Java, c#/.net, Oracle, MS Sql server, Javascript
- Deliver high quality custom softwares for users in multiple industries. Help users to make more efficient production plans, reduce lead time by 10%+, reduce material cost, timely collection production data, manage e-commerce orders and stock, etc.
- Design and write unit tests, integrated tests and system tests.
- Implement softwares in factories and offer on-going support

Sep 1999 - July 2001

Finet.hk company, Shenzhen, China - Database Developer

• Define database specifications. Write sql query. Replicate, backup, profile Oracle database.

Aug 1996 - July 1999

Gezhouba Group, Yichang, China- Senior Software Engineer and Project manager

 Develop a custom application to manage hydroelectricity project cost using VB and SqlServer

Education

Sep 1992 - July 1996

Nankai university, Tianjin - Bachelor of computer and information

Languages

English, French, Japanese, Mandarin